VICTOR SCHOLZ

(407) 353-5174 | vgscholz@gmail.com | Brooklyn, NY | Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub | Medium

SUMMARY

Driven software engineer with experience building full stack applications with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, SQL databases, and RESTful API architecture. A background in the service industry combines a proficiency in collaboration and team empowerment, with a passion for problem solving.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, React, Three.js, Cannon.js, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Postgres, PostGis, SQL, Git, Heroku

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Aeropress Dice - Demo | Video | GitHub

3D Physics based application inspired by the Aeropress dice product that allows the user to roll the dice and save recipes.

- Created in React with the React-Three-Fiber and Use-Cannon libraries in conjunction with a Rails back-end.
- Constructed a reactive scene with lighting conditions, objects, textures, and shadows with the Three.js library.
- Loaded in custom built and textured 3D gITF models and resized them to the scene.
- Randomized the set velocity, rotation, and position for each dice when thrown on click.
- Added sound effects to the dice throw and recipe save buttons with the use-sound library and imported .wav files.
- Rendered the results of each roll on the plane while utilizing React Hooks to manage state.

District Build NYC - Demo | Video | GitHub

An interactive map of NYC that allows the user to click on any of the 37,000 historical buildings and see it's information.

- Built a React front-end with a custom MapboxGL.js map and a Rails back-end utilizing a PostGis database.
- Produced an extensive schema for the buildings in conjunction with ActiveModelSerializers to reorganize the data for the front-end.
- Seeded database with a GeoJSON file from NYC Open Data and loaded that information into the map as a clickable layer.
- Used HTML, CSS, and MapboxGL.js to create a marker and description modal for a building once it is clicked.

Churn - GitHub

An application that keeps track of credit cards currently available along with their associated fees and categories.

- Communicated with the CCstack RESTful API endpoint to render credit card information through Rails back-end.
- Engineered user interface using JavaScript and improved user experience with responsive design techniques.

EXPERIENCE

THE ESPRESSO SPECIALIST

Brooklyn, NY

Service Manager

Sept. 2019 - July 2020

- Coordinated all scheduling of service and operation of coffee equipment for 3,000 accounts in New York, New Jersey, and Connecticut.
- Handled all invoicing for repair and install work that averaged \$36,000 per week across three technicians.

THE GLASS KNIFE

Winter Park, FL

Beverage Program Director

July 2018 – June 2019

- Oversaw and led the hiring of a six-person beverage team as well as the drink menu creation for the business.
- Became Onyx Coffee Lab's highest grossing wholesale account with over \$110,000 spent on coffee in one year.

EDUCATION

FLATIRON SCHOOL

New York, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript programming bootcamp

July 2020 - Oct. 2020

FLORIDA STATE UNIVERSITY - COLLEGE OF SOCIAL SCIENCES

Tallahassee, FL

Bachelor of Science, Interdisciplinary Social Sciences

Sept. 2014 - June 2018

Concentrations in Social Entrepreneurship and Economics